<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TKLab Wiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/active-projects/cryosamba/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TKLab Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/docs/active-projects/cryosamba/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BioArchive</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/active-projects/cryosamba/paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/active-projects/cryosamba/paper/</guid>
      <description>CryoSamba: Self-Supervised Cryo-ET Image Denoising # Abstract # Cryogenic electron tomography (cryo-ET) has rapidly advanced as a high-resolution imaging tool for visualizing subcellular structures in 3D with molecular detail. Direct image inspection remains challenging due to inherent low signal-to-noise ratios (SNR). We introduce CryoSamba, a self-supervised deep learning-based model designed for denoising cryo-ET images. CryoSamba enhances single consecutive 2D planes in tomograms by averaging motion-compensated nearby planes through deep learning interpolation, effectively mimicking increased exposure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CryoSamba Main</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/active-projects/cryosamba/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/active-projects/cryosamba/project/</guid>
      <description>CryoSamba: Self-Supervised Deep Volumetric Denoising for Cryo-Electron Tomography Data # For Hardware Issues please refer to the Nvidia-CUDA section # For Software Issues please refer to the Python section, Using Conda Environment # This repository contains the denoising pipeline described in the following publication:&#xA;Jose Inacio Costa-Filho, Liam Theveny, Marilina de Sautu, Tom KirchhausenCryoSamba: Self-Supervised Deep Volumetric Denoising for Cryo-Electron Tomography Data&#xA;Please cite this publication if you are using this code in your research.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Scratch(Advanced)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/active-projects/cryosamba/advanced/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/active-projects/cryosamba/advanced/</guid>
      <description>Advanced instructions # Table of Contents # Installation 🐍 Training Setup Training 🛠️ Run Training 🚀 Visualization with TensorBoard 📈 Inference Setup Inference 🛠️ Run Inference 🚀 Installation # Open a terminal window and run conda create --name your-env-name python=3.11 -y to create the environment (replace your-env-name with a desired name). Activate the environment with conda activate your-env-name. In the future, you will have to activate the environment anytime you want to use CryoSamba.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
